John P. Wodarski collection 1931-2002 CPAA 86-02
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain
John P. Wodarski collection
1931-2002
John P. Wodarski
CPAA 86-02
17 boxes (9 linear ft.)
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University
Monsignor John P. Wodarski collection is unique in terms of portraying and documenting activities of an ethnic Polish American parish and material related to the history of the Catholic Church and history of Poland. Msgr. John P. Wodarski was a pastor at the Holy Cross church in New Britain, Connecticut for several decades. Msgr. Wodarski was a very innovative priest who applied his ideas into educating the local community and always looked for ways to promote mutual understanding among other ethnic and religious groups. He was a great supporter of the Polish Studies Program at Central Connecticut State University where he served on the advisory board for many years. The collection includes documentation of the celebration of Poland's Millennium in 1966 and visit by Cardinal Karol Wojtyla from communist Poland to the US in 1969. Cardinal Wojtyla later became Pope John Paul II.
Historical/Biographical Note
Monsignor John Paul Wodarski (1905-2002) was a long time pastor of the Holy Cross Catholic Church in New Britain, Connecticut. He was born on September 20, 1905 in Salem, MA. He was educated in catholic schools in Hartford and later attended St. Mary's College in Orchard Lake, MI and studied theology at the University of Fribourg, in Switzerland, where he was ordained to the priesthood in 1931. His first pastoral assignments from 1931 till 1944 were at St. Stanislaus in Bristol, St. Joseph in Willimantic and St. Mary in Putnam. Between 1944 and 1946 he was the US Army Chaplain. Msgr. Wodarski worked as director of Youth and CCD program in the Archdiocese of Hartford. He received the title of Monsignor in 1957 and became pastor of the Holy Cross church in New Britain in 1961, where he retired in 1992.
Msgr. Wodarski had extended interest in Polish affairs and history and in 1969 he helped to organize a visit to the United States of Cardinal Karol Wojtyla of Krakow, Poland who later became the Pope John Paul II. Msgr. Wodarski was an active member in many church, state and civic organizations and for his tireless work he received many awards and recognitions. His active involvements lead him to receive the doctorate Honoris Causa from Catholic University in Lublin in 1995 and from Central Connecticut State University (CCSU) in 1999. Msgr. Wodarski was a very active advocate for Polish cause and great supporter of the Polish Studies program at CCSU in New Britain. Monsignor John Wodarski died on October 12, 2002 and is buried at the Sacred Heart cemetery in New Britain.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The collection includes personal papers, Polish American Priests Association records, other documents, clippings and correspondence related to Monsignor's activities and pastoral appointments. Collection includes also publications from the US and Poland related to the history of Catholic Church and Polish American issues on the national and local level.
The collection is open for research.
Majority of the material was donated in 1986 to the archives by Msgr. John P. Wodarski. Material dated after 1986 was send to the library every two to three years. Last donation of the material was made by Msgr. Wodarski's secretary after his death.
Search Terms
Wodarski, John P. (John Paul), 1905-2002; Catholic Church -- Connecticut.; Catholic Church -- Clergy.; Association of Polish Priests in Connecticut.; Clergy -- Connecticut.; Catholics, Polish -- Connecticut.; Polish Americans -- Religious life -- Connecticut.; Correspondence.; Pamphlets.; Photographs.; Clippings.
Related Material
For related material see the following collections:
Alphonse P. Fiedorczyk Papers, CPAA 88-06
Henry Fiedorczyk Papers, CPAA 04-13
Association of Polish Priests of Connecticut records, CPAA 86-03
Arrangement
The material in the collection is arranged in eight series. Folders within each series are in chronological order:
Series I Personal and family related papers.
Series II Holy Cross Catholic Church.
Series III Association of Polish Priests of Connecticut (APPC).
Series IV Millennium of Poland's Christianity.
Series V Pope John Paul II.
Series VI Maximilian Kolbe Canonization and Beatification.
Series VII Rev. Boleslaw Kumor's writings.
Series VIII General - books, pamphlets, scrapbooks.
Container List
[The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.]
- Series I: Personal and family related papers., 1945-2002
  - Wodarski Family Tree., 1895-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Wodarski family stages of life card., 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Order Kawalerski Polonia Restituta for Msgr. John P. Wodarski, 1969. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Thank you letter from Karol Cardinal Wojtyla after his visit to the New Britain (photocopy)., October, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten notes for an article about John P. Wodarski by Stanislaus A. Blejwas., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter soliciting support for Polish Heritage Collection at CCSU., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Articles and editorials by Msgr. John P. Wodarski., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fidelitas Medal for Msgr. John P. Wodarski, Orchard Lake Schools., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - News clippings related to Msgr. Wodarski., 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notes on my (Msgr. Wodarski) pilgrimage to Rome and an audience with the Pope., January 10, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Msgr. John P. Wodarski - photos from events., 1964-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Medal za zaslugi dla KUL-u,(photocopy)., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Right Rev. Msgr. John P. Wodarski - 60th Anniversary of Priesthood 1931-91 and 30th anniversary as Pastor of Holy Cross Church 1961-1991., 1931-1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Cardinal Stefan Wyszynski, Polish Primate,(photocopy., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Golden Jubilee of Priesthood of Msgr. Wodarski, program and keynote address by Prof. Stanislaus A. Blejwas., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Monsignor Wodarski's 25th Silver Jubilee of Pastorate of the Holy Cross, program and 2 photographs of Msgr. Wodarski with Msgr A. Fiedorczyk, Rev. Solega, and unknown priest., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter from Archbishop John Whealon re: greetings from the Pope to Msgr. Wodarski., 1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Honorary Doctorate for Msgr. John P. Wodarski from the Catholic University of Lublin, Poland - official invitation, program, congratulatory letters, photographs, press clippings., June 22 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Awards, a scrapbook compiled by Msgr. John P. Wodarski., 1945-1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Prof. Stanislaus A. Blejwas - obituaries, in memoriam., 2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Rev. John P. Wodarski obituary., October 12, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 2 posters - Wodarski Family Tree., 1899 - 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series II: Holy Cross Catholic church
  - List of Budget Envelope Contributions., 1961-1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Organ Dedication, Holy Cross Church., November 13, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Holy Cross Parish Handbook., 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Holy Cross Church - deeds (photocopies)., 1928, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut Polish Bicentennial Program at Holy Cross., 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Anniversary booklets and programs for area priests and organizations., 1946-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Holy Cross Golden Jubilee, program, newsletters, publications., 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dzieje Polskiej Rzymsko-Katolickiej parafii Swietego Krzyza w New Britain, Conn. (1927-1977), by Ks. Boleslaw Kumor. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript and notes - Dzieje Polskiej Rzymsko-Katolickiej parafii Swietego Krzyza w New Britain, Conn. (1927-1977), by Ks. Boleslaw Kumor. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Stanislaus A. Blejwas, manuscript of "A Polish community in transition"., 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "A Polish community in transition: the origins and evolution of Holy Cross Parish, New Britain, Connecticut", by Stanislaus A. Blejwas., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Holy Cross Church Silver Jubilee - 2 sound recording tapes., November 16, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Letter to Msgr. John P. Wodarski from the Pope John Paul II Polish-American Foundation regarding proposal to help recent Polish refugees., 1984 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Beata Galon murder and burial controversy, Sacred Heart cemetary, New Britain,(press clippings)., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Series III: Association of Polish Priests of Connecticut (APPC), 1968-1991
  - Meeting agendas, minutes and related correspondence., 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Meeting agendas, minutes and related correspondence., 1971-1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Meeting minutes and report., 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 50th Anniversary of Independence of Poland, master file., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 50th Anniversary of Independence of Poland, correspondence., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 50th Anniversary of Independence of Poland, programs., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 50th Anniversary of Independence of Poland, minutes and memos, clippings., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 50th Anniversary of Independence of Poland, finances and tickets., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tribute to Mary Queen of Poland on the 50th anniversary of the regaining of Independence by Poland., May 4, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 50th Anniversary of Independence of Poland - photographs., May 4, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - APPC annual mass for deceased members., 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bishop Jerzy Dabrowski visit to Connecticut., October 1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Cardinal Henryk Gulbinowicz of Poland visit to Connecticut., April 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Association of Polish Priests in Connecticut, an interpretative history, by Rev. Theophil T. Mierzwinski., 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - St. Thomas seminary vignettes. A statistical glance at the first quarter-century of St. Thomas Seminary (1897-1921)., undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Rev. Stephen Bratkowski 50th Anniversary of Priesthood, article from New Britain Herald., October 27, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - St. Stanislaus Kostka school, Bristol, Connecticut - First graduates photograph, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - APPC - letter head and mailing labels. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - New Britain area conferences of churches - program, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - APPC - constitution., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ethnic parishes' debate and ethnic pride materials, letters, clippings., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ethnic parish debate letter from Msgr. John P. Wodarski to Cardinal John Krol, letters from Judge William Bieluch., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bojnowski Biography Project - correspondence and clippings, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bojnowski Biography Project - letters and book reviews., 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Polish contributions to American history and civilization - clippings., 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Open letter from Archbishop J. Bernardin, President of National Conference of Catholic Bishops of the United States., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bishop Lech Kaczmarek visit in Connecticut - master file., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Bishop Lech Kaczmarek visit in Connecticut - finances., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Bishop Lech Kaczmarek visit in Connecticut - news coverage., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Bishop Lech Kaczmarek visit in Connecticut - correspondence., 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Bishop Lech Kaczmarek visit in Connecticut - photographs., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 41st International Eucharistic Congress - program in English and Polish., August 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Holocaust Remembrance Day - program, list of participants., April 29, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Holocaust Remembrance Day - news coverage., April 29, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Holocaust Remembrance Day - letters, April 29, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Holocaust Remembrance Day - scrap book., April 29, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Polish Americans and the media presentation of the Holocaust" essay by Prof. Stanislaus A. Blejwas., 1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - APPC correspondence related to financial contribution to catholic church in Poland., 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - APPC Fifth Annual Convention, Hartford, Connecticut., April, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - APPC Rally for Solidarity - appeals, list of speakers, flyer, poster, clippings., December 1981 (Box 5A, Folder 1)
  - Association of Polish Priests of Conn., Connecticut State AFLO-CIO and Polish American Congress - Rally for Freedom in Poland, list of supporters., December 20, 1981 (Box 5A, Folder 2)
  - APPC Food for Poland - benefit concert, minutes, clippings, flyers., March 1982 (Box 5A, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Catholic Relief Services regarding support for Solidarity., 1981-1982 (Box 5A, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Pope John Paul II Foundation with proposal to help recent Polish refugees., 1984 (Box 5A, Folder 5)
  - Clippings - situation in Poland and Eastern Europe., 1980 (Box 5A, Folder 6)
  - Clippings - situation in Poland, Solidarity and reactions from local community, from American media., 1981-1983 (Box 5A, Folder 7)
  - Clippings on situation in Poland and Solidarity from Polish American media., 1981-1982 (Box 5A, Folder 8)
  - Jozef Cardinal Glemp, Polish Primate, visit to Connecticut for the Century of Polonia celebration, photo album, 1991 (Box 5B, Folder 1)
  - St. Joseph church, Diamond Jubilee, Norwich, CT - 3 photographs., 1979 (Box 5B, Folder 2)
  - Cardinal Stefan Wyszynski, Polish Primate, photos, biographical information, clippings., 1970-1985 (Box 5B, Folder 3)
  - Msgr. Alphonse P. Fiedorczyk, obituary from Duszpasterz Polski za Granica in Polish (photocopy)., 1989 (Box 5B, Folder 4)
  - Rev. Henry Fiedorczyk "That's my brother" [about Msgr. Alphonse Fiedorczyk], 1990 (Box 5B, Folder 5)
  - Cultural events flyers., 1980's (Box 5B, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous - prayer cards, photographs from religious sites in Poland, undated (Box 5B, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook - clippings from Dziennik dla Wszystkich., 1951-1952 (Box 5B, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Millennium of Poland's Christianity, 1966
  - Correspondence with prospective guests and speakers., 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with various organizations from Polonia and Poland., 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Preparation material, programs, related correspondence., 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Survey among Polish clergy and nuns on the Catholic faith distributed by Msgr. John P. Wodarski for local television programs in preparation for the Millennium celebration., 1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Celebration programs from various places., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of the Millennium Committee meetings., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - News releases, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Tickets sale., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Badges, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Thank you notes., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Stamps, envelopes, pins, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Polish American Congress., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Publications for the Millennium in Polish and English., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Wielka Nowenna Narodu by Rev. Zdzislaw Peszkowski., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Information on events related to the Millennium., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - An Episcopal letter from Archbishop Henry J. O'Brien of Hartford for the support of the catholic church in Poland., June 9, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Pamphlets, programs, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Magazines with information about the Millennium: Hejnal Mariacki, Jasna Gora, The Immaculate, and Meet Poland., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Resource material., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Information on Polish films., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Collection of photographs from various Millennium events., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Series V: Pope John Paul II, 1969-1985
  - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla's Visit - Correspondence., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla's Visit - Printed program and information bulletins., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla's Visit - responses from the area priests., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla's Visit - reception list of participants, ticket distribution., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla's Visit - finances., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla's Visit - itinerary, press releases and related correspondence., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla's Visit - press clippings., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla's Visit - photographs and negatives., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla's Visit, Thank you letter from the cardinal to Msgr. Wodarski and general thank you letter to Polonia (photocopies)., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Cardinal Karol Wojtyla's visit to Montreal, Canada - 2 photographs and press clippings., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Tribute to Pope John Paul II election celebration - master file material for the event., November 12, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Tribute to John Paul II, scarapbook., November 12, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Tribute to John Paul II, correspondence, list of participants, program., November 12, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Letters received about the election of Pope John Paul II., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Tribute to John Paul II, press releases., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Tribute to Pope John Paul II, finances., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Tribute to Pope John Paul II, scripts: Prof. Buczek, Rev. Fiedorczyk., November 12, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - John Paul II - holy cards., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Tribute to John Paul II - Central Connecticut State College, rental contract for Welte Hall., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Pope John Paul II election - reaction by the local Polish community, press clippings., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Holy Cross parish pilgrimage to Rome - notes by Msgr. John P. Wodarski, photo with the Pope., 1979 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Images of John Paul II., 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Election of John Paul II, articles from various periodicals., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Pope John Paul II first visit to the US - Holy Cross parish participation in Mass in Boston., October 1, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Pope John paul II first visit to the US - programs, articles, clippings., 1979 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Pope John Paul II - first anniversary of his election, clippings, articles., 1979 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Pope John Paul II - articles from periodicals on Pope's visits to different countries., 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Pope John Paul II - publications about visits to Ireland, England, Wales and US., 1980-1987 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Pope John Paul II - various clippings and writings., 1980's (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Pope John Paul II - visit to the US., 1987 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Clippings and articles on religious issues., 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Pope John Paul II Cultural Center campaign., 1995 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Witness of Hope, book by George Weigel, book reviews and clippings., 1999 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Bibliography of writings of Carol Cardinal Wojtyla and Pope John Paul II for the years 1949-1978, by Rev. Roman Nir. (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Newspapers and clippings with information about Karol Cardinal Wojtyla's visit in New Britain, Sep. 18, 1969 and on his election to Papacy in October 1978., 1969, 1978 (Box 9, Folder flat)
- Series VI: Maximilian Maria Kolbe Canonization and Beatification, 1971, 1982
  - Pamphlets and magazines about Maximilian Maria Kolbe (in Polish and In English)., 1970-1980 (Box 13)
  - Holy Cross pilgrimage to Rome - Maximilian Kolbe beatification, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - M. Kolbe Beatification - clippings., 1971 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - M. Kolbe Canonization - information pocket for pilgrims, pamphlets, holy cards, medallions, photographs., 1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - M. Kolbe - articles about canonization., 1982 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - M. Kolbe canonization - charges of anti-semitism by some Jewish circles., 1982 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Holy Cross pilgrimage to Rome - Maximilian Kolbe canonization., 1982 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Promotional material on Maximilian Kolbe and the Franciscan pilgrimage., 1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets on Maximilian Kolbe canonization., 1982 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Series VII: Rev. Boleslaw Kumor's writings, 1979-1982
  - Rev. Boleslaw Kumor - photograph., undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Rev. Boleslaw Kumor - photograph with the Pope John Paul II., 1981 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Koscielne Dzieje Polonii w Connecticut 1870-1986. Wybrane zagadnienia. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Dzieje Parafii Polskiej Rzymsko-Katolickiej, Sw. Michala Archaniola w Derby, CT 1905-1975(photocopy). (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Dzieje Polskiej Parafii Sw. Krzyza w New Britain, Connecticut, 1927-1977.(photocopy)., 1978 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - VHS tape - Rev. Boleslaw Kumor's church in Niskowo, Poland., 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Dzieje Parafii Polskiej Rzymsko-Katolickiej Sw. Jozefa w Norwich, Connecticut, 1904-1979. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Polonia i Polska Parafia Rzymsko-Katolicka SS. Cyryla I Metodego w Hartford, Connecticut, 1873-1980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - SS. Cyril and Methodius Parish and the Hartford Polonia, 1873-1980. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - History of Polonia and of the Polish Parish of St. Joseph in Suffield, Conn. 1884-1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Dzieje Polonii i Katolickiej Parafii Polskiej Sw. Jozefa w Suffield, Connecticut, 1884 -1981. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - St. Joseph, Suffield, Conn. Translation of Rev. Kumor book into English by Msgr. Alphonse Fiedorczyk, pt.1, August 1986 (handwritten) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Koscielne dzieje Polonii w Connecticut 1870-1986, by Rev. Boleslaw Kumor, published in Poland., 1990 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Series VIII: General - books, pamphlets, scrap books
  - 2 scrapbooks with clippings and articles about former Polish president Lech Walesa and his visit to New Britain, Connecticut., April, 1996 (Box 15, Folder flat)
  - DVD from Lech Walesa visit to CCSU., April 11, 1996 (Box 15, Folder flat)
  - Books and pamphlets in Polish. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Books and pamphlets in English. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Books and pamphlets on religious topics. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Scrap book on Rev. Paul Wysocki and Secret Heart Church in New Britain controversy., 1987-1988 (Box 19, Folder flat)